[Music]
welcome back you're watching the money
show on ET now as the Corona virus
pandemic GPS the nation the world I'm
sure that one question that may be on
your mind is that God forbid if me or my
family members contract this deadly
disease will my insurance policy cover
it will I have the financial ammunition
to provide uh the needed care and the
medical support to myself or the my
loved one God forbid if they should
contract the disease and also will your
current policy cover it will you need a
top up will the Quantum of the sum short
be be enough that's what we will discuss
let me bring on board Mr Sanjay data of
icsa Lumar General Insurance company uh
San thank you so much for joining us on
the money show let's start off first
with a very simple basic question I have
my regular health insurance policy that
I'm paying for perhaps for myself
maybe for my family as well the simple
question is will that existing policy
cover a disease like Corona virus
s our existing hospitalization policy
will cover Corona uh both in case uh you
are diagnosed and you having treatment
for it or in case uh you hospitalized
and are quarantined for
it what about Group Policy a lot of our
viewers right now are of course salary
they're covered in their company's medic
claim policy would that be
sufficient yes you know you would get
covered under you know a group policy
which your company may have taken or you
personally may have taken a retail
insurance insurance policy on an inity
basis where you will get
C okay San what about the need for a
critical insurance policy uh is that
required would I be better off just take
out that additional policy along with my
regular medic
claim you know critical insurance
policies uh on a named basis so normally
they are for critical you know you know
illnesses uh they may not cover covid
insurance so you may need to take a
specific cover for covid in case uh you
want covid coverage uh
so most of your critical inness cover
you know would cover uh cancer or you
know heart
diseases now you know sanj we've been
talking about living in a postc Corona
virus world as well um things definitely
will change quite a bit once we come out
of this crisis would my premium cost be
one of them can we expect higher premium
costs uh I mean uh you know for your
benefit critical illness policies no
because they don't cover of it but for
uh you know the uh your health insurance
policy which is a policy which covers
all diseases uh you know uh we'll have
to wait and watch uh you know hopefully
uh you know uh if the impact or of covid
virus illnesses on the health insurance
portfolio of the insurers are not too
high you know there may not be any
substantial remission uh you know so
we'll have to wait and once
okay God forbid let's say I've
contracted the Corona virus is there any
criteria under which my claim with the
insurance company could be
denied yeah uh of course you know if you
have just taken a policy and you are
within the 30 days uh your claim could
be denied because there's a 30-day you
know waiting period for Ines which are
you know which is there and uh so so to
that extent yes but after that uh if you
do contract Co it would be
covered specific you know covid covers
which are now there have certain waiting
periods so even that uh on that also
there needs to be a waiting period but
after the waiting period it what is the
status on making claims then I mean
obviously you know since the Prime
Minister as well has put the country on
lockdown um many companies are operating
on skeletal staff um so how could
viewers go about making their claims
with the insurance
companies so you know uh I I think this
is the right moment to you know go and
make a claim uh you know uh for a
hospitalization claims of course you go
to the hospital and the hospital
processes in uh and you can yourself
register a claim you know online as for
your reimbursement claims you you can go
you know uh online and register your
claim and and follow the necessary
process so uh there are workarounds
which are now being made available so
yes you need to go online and register
your clim and you know report that a has
been made and you need to submit
necessary documents to aade the
benefit okay great um lovely to get in
your take thanks so much Sanja I hope
this was informative for a lot of our
viewers wondering what could be the
financial ramifications God forbid if
they or their family members contracts
this deadly virus we'll wrap it up on
the money show thank you for watching
[Music]